1909 Hudson-Fulton Celebration Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 11. Miscellany, 1907-1909; 0.21 linear feet 1 Box (Box 25)
  - P.S.O. of A. Hudson-Fulton Parade Memo, Small tear in top center edge. Small stain in upper left corner. Faint creasing across paper from previous folding. Large crease in bottom right corner. Small creases across bottom. Paper is very brittle. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Letter, dated May 29, 1909, from P.S.O. of A. elected officials requesting that representatives from their organization’s camps in New Jersey and New York be sent to Tuxedo Hall, Madison Ave, and 59th Street in NYC on April 21, 1909 to form an organization to enlist members to participate in Hudson-Fulton Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - P.S.O. of A. Attendance Pledge Sheet, Creases throughout from previous folding. Faint stain along crease on the center right. Two small tears along top center edge. Small tear in bottom right edge. Various small creases around edges. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Blank attendance pledge sheet for the men who volunteered to be in the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Parade in NYC on Tuesday, September 28, 1909. Watermark on paper from Swiss Bond.
  - Patriotic Sons Order of America HF Parade Letter, Small, faint stain on bottom right. Large stain across top to center from paper previously stored with sheet. Writing on other paper visible within stain. Bottom left corner tip missing. Creases throughout from previous folding. Two small tears along top center edge. Paper is very brittle. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Letter, dated July 19, 1909, from Hudson-Fulton Celebration Committee of the Patriotic Sons Order of America of New York State addressed to all members. Letter was sent to all P.S.O. of A. camps in New Jersey and New York. The contents of the letter invite and encourage men to participate in the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Parade in NYC on September 28, 1909.
  - Hudson-Fulton Parade Stands Designs, Faint staining across back. Faint stain along back, left edge from previous erased handwritten note. Very slight fraying of corners. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Paper outlining scheme of designs to be followed in decoration of stands for the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Parade. Paper features sketches of various areas where the parade will pass and how the stands and decorations should be. Designs courtesy of Chas. R. Lamb, Chairman of Committee on Decorations and Reviewing Stands. Paper was previously folded into fourths. Paper also features watermark for Brookdale Linen Bond, NY.
  - Half-Moon and Clermont Reproduction Building Plans, Small tear in top center edge. Small stain in upper left corner. Faint creasing across paper from previous folding. Large crease in bottom right corner. Small creases across bottom. Paper is very brittle. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Set of ship building plans—one for “Half-Moon” and one for “Clermont”. Plans feature sketches of the various aspects of each ship. Each is folded several times.
  - Half-Moon and Clermont Reproduction Building Plans #2, Large creases from top to bottom on both leaves. Small stain on back bottom right. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Hudson-Fulton Celebration Photo Collage, Paper is brittle. Along center fold is very fragile. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Black and white photo collage of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration from the Albany Evening Journal, October 25, 1909. Photos by an Evening Journal staff photographer. The photos are dated October 7-8, 1909 and showcase the celebration festivities in Albany, NY. Each photograph features a number with a matching blurb located at the bottom of page.